Society for Canadian Women in Science and Technology fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Projects, programs and events files, 1981 - 2004; F-39-5; Analog originals: 1.74 m of textual records 13 photographs 19 sound recordings (25 audio cassettes) 1 multiple media record (1 optical disk - CD)
  - Work Pathfinder program files, 1994 - 1999; F-39-5-6; 12 cm of textual records 1 multiple media record; Physical description: sub-series includes 1 CD.
    Sub-series comprises records relating to operation of the Work Pathfinder program, designed to provide girls and women with information and resources about science careers through development of web sites and a CD ROM. Records consists of correspondence; reports; grant applications and supporting documentation; contracts; and design planning documents.
    - Xplore Science Careers, 1998; F-39-5-6-0-0-1 (Optical disc: cd OBJ-2222)
      Multi-media
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-39-item32.
    - Exploring careers in Science, 1997; F-39-5-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 39-13)
    - Grants and applications, 1994 - 1996; F-39-5-6-0-2 (Archival box - standard 39-13)
    - Grants and applications, 1996 - 1997; F-39-5-6-0-3 (Archival box - standard 39-13)
    - Correspondence, 1995; F-39-5-6-0-4 (Archival box - standard 39-23)
    - Correspondence, vol. 1, 1995 - 1996; F-39-5-6-0-5 (Archival box - standard 39-23)
    - Correspondence, vol. 2, 1995 - 1996; F-39-5-6-0-6 (Archival box - standard 39-23)
    - Website, 1996; F-39-5-6-0-7 (Archival box - standard 39-23)
    - CD ROM production, vol. 1, 1996 - 1997; F-39-5-6-0-8 (Archival box - standard 39-23)
    - CD ROM production, vol. 2, 1996 - 1997; F-39-5-6-0-9 (Archival box - standard 39-23)
    - Explore science careers CD ROM, 1998 - 1999; F-39-5-6-0-10 (Archival box - standard 39-23)
    - Grant CD ROM, 1999; F-39-5-6-0-11 (Archival box - standard 39-23)
  - Ms Infinity program files, 1991 - 2003; F-39-5-7; 34 cm of textual records
    Sub-series comprises records relating to the development and delivery of the Ms Infinity program, a series of one-day conferences for young women in grades 9 and 10 in British Columbia and the Yukon to attend hands-on workshops, presentations and panel sessions that provide information about career options for women in science and technology. The program was started in 1990 and continues in existence. Ms Infinity conferences are organized by the local communities while SCWIST provides a manual and video, training for the community liaison person, and expenses and honoraria for workshop leaders. Records consist of correspondence, reports; committee meeting minutes and supporting papers; grant applications and supporting documentation; workshop presentation materials, including overheads and transparencies; manuals and handbooks; and publicity brochures.
    - Committee meeting - minutes, 1992 - 1994; F-39-5-7-0-1 (Archival box - standard 39-13)
    - Conference guide, 1993; F-39-5-7-0-2 (Archival box - standard 39-13)
    - Conference guide, 1994; F-39-5-7-0-3 (Archival box - standard 39-13)
    - Conferences, 1994 - 1997; F-39-5-7-0-4 (Archival box - standard 39-13)
    - External review, 1995; F-39-5-7-0-5 (Archival box - standard 39-13)
    - Finances, 1992 - 1993; F-39-5-7-0-6 (Archival box - standard 39-13)
    - Grants and applications, 1992 - 1993; F-39-5-7-0-7 (Archival box - standard 39-13)
    - Handbook, 1992; F-39-5-7-0-8 (Archival box - standard 39-14)
    - Presentations, 1991 - 1997; F-39-5-7-0-9 (Archival box - standard 39-14)
    - Publicity -video, 1995 - 1997; F-39-5-7-0-10 (Archival box - standard 39-14)
    - Conferences, 1993; F-39-5-7-0-11 (Archival box - standard 39-24)
    - Conferences, 1994; F-39-5-7-0-12 (Archival box - standard 39-24)
    - Conferences, 1995; F-39-5-7-0-13 (Archival box - standard 39-24)
    - Conferences, 1996; F-39-5-7-0-14 (Archival box - standard 39-24)
    - Infinite Options newsletter, 1993 - 2003; F-39-5-7-0-15 (Archival box - standard 39-24)
    - Coordinator's file, 1994 - 2003; F-39-5-7-0-16 (Archival box - standard 39-24)
    - Grants and reports, 1995 - 1998; F-39-5-7-0-17 (Archival box - standard 39-24)
    - Final report, 1996; F-39-5-7-0-18 (Archival box - standard 39-24)
    - Grants, 1998 - 1999; F-39-5-7-0-19 (Archival box - standard 39-24)
    - Grants - beyond Ms. Infinity, 1998 - 1999; F-39-5-7-0-20 (Archival box - standard 39-25)
    - Role model manual, 1999; F-39-5-7-0-21 (Archival box - standard 39-25)
    - Telementoring, 1999 - 2001; F-39-5-7-0-22 (Archival box - standard 39-25)
  - Female Friendly Science Teaching program files, 1991 - 1993; F-39-5-8; 5 cm of textual records
    Sub-series comprises records relating to the development and delivery of the Female Friendly Science Teaching, begun in 1991 to develop teaching strategies for helping young women feel more at ease with the physical sciences and to promote these strategies, primarily through publications and handbooks. Records consist of correspondence; reports; grant applications and supporting documentation; handbooks and manuals; and evaluation forms.
    - Female Friendly Science Teaching committee, 1991 - 1993; F-39-5-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 39-14)
    - Female Friendly Science Teaching committee - resource book, 1992 - 1993; F-39-5-8-0-2 (Archival box - standard 39-14)
- Public relations files, 1981 - 2005; F-39-6; 33 cm of textual records 2 artifacts
  Series comprises records relating to the Society's interactions with the public in order to communicate its goals, activities and accomplishments. Activities documented include production of the newsletter SCWIST News and publicity brochures; maintenance of Society membership and naming of honorary members; nomination of Society members for external awards and honours; responses to requests for support and funding; and administration of SCWIST scholarships. Records consist of correspondence; reports; award applications and supporting documentation; committee meeting minutes; grant applications and supporting documentation; membership forms and lists; honorary member certificates; newsletters, publicity brochures and artifacts (buttons).
  - Awards - nominations, 1997; F-39-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Awards - YWCA Woman of Distinction nomination, 1991; F-39-6-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Fundraising, 1993 - 1994; F-39-6-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Fundraising - Casino, 1990; F-39-6-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Membership forms, 1981 - 1988; F-39-6-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Membership - honorary members, 1991; F-39-6-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Membership - lists, 1981 - 1994; F-39-6-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Publications - newsletter (SCWIST News), 1983 - 1995; F-39-6-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Publicity - brochures, 1982 - 1995; F-39-6-0-0-9; Physical description: file includes 2 artifacts (buttons). (Archival box - standard 39-15)
    Textual records; Artefacts
    - Rocket scientist poster, [199-?]; F-39-6-0-0-9-1 (Print OBJ-3077)
      Graphic materials
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-39-item31.
  - Scholarships, 1987 - 1995; F-39-6-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Support and Partnership, 1992 - 1994; F-39-6-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Support and Partnership - Michael Smith fund, 1996; F-39-6-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Support and Partnership - policy, 1985; F-39-6-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Support and Partnership - requests for funding, 1992; F-39-6-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 39-15)
  - Announcements and flyers, 1982 - 1997; F-39-6-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 39-25)
  - News clippings, 1990 - 1994; F-39-6-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 39-25)
  - Fundraising - casino, 1990 - 1995; F-39-6-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 39-25)
  - Fundraising - casino, vol. 1, 1996 - 1998; F-39-6-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 39-25)
  - Fundraising - casino, vol. 2, 1996 - 1998; F-39-6-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 39-25)
  - Membership awards - Hilda Ching, Joe Quan, 1991 - 2003; F-39-6-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
  - Fundraising - general, 1992 - 1998; F-39-6-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
  - Michael Smith - reference material, 1993 - 2000; F-39-6-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
  - XX Evening, 1994 - 1997; F-39-6-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
  - XX Evening, 1997; F-39-6-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
  - XX Evening, 1997 - 1998; F-39-6-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
  - XX Evening, 1999; F-39-6-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
  - Michael Smith award nomination - Hilda Ching, 1996; F-39-6-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
  - SCWIST newsletter, 1996 - 2004; F-39-6-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
  - Volunteer orientation binder, 2000; F-39-6-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
  - Student awards and thank-you cards, 2004 - 2005; F-39-6-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 39-26)
- Photographs, 1983 - 2001; F-39-7; 390 photographs
  Series consists of informal snapshots of various SCWIST social, administrative, fundraising, and educational activities.
  The series was created and arranged by the archivist to accommodate snapshots from photo albums and scrapbooksas well as loose photos received as part of an accrual of records from SCWIST.
  - SCWIST conference, 1983; F-39-7-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - SCWIST fall picnic, 1987; F-39-7-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Girls in science, 1988; F-39-7-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Women do math, 1988 - 1990; F-39-7-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Career pathfinders, [199-?]; F-39-7-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Various events, 1991 - 1999; F-39-7-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Chilliwack, 1992; F-39-7-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Executive planning session, 1992; F-39-7-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Opening of resource centre, 1992; F-39-7-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Michael Smith party at Mary Vickers's house, 1994; F-39-7-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Women of distinction, 1994; F-39-7-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Kamloops conference--women do math, 1995; F-39-7-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Ms. Infinity, Houston B.C., 1995; F-39-7-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - P.T. interaction day, Trout Lake, Oct. 21, 1995., F-39-7-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Girl Guides, 1996; F-39-7-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Ms. Infinity, 1997 - 2001; F-39-7-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - SCWIST AGM, 1997; F-39-7-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - XX Evening, 1997; F-39-7-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - Science Week, SFU, 1997; F-39-7-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - XX Evening, 2000; F-39-7-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 39-27)
  - SCWIST 20th birthday party, 2001; F-39-7-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 39-27)